Jack Simm

Product Designer/ Product Development Manager

An experienced time served Mechanical Maintenance Technician with a proven track record in manufacturing. I have over a half-decade of manufacturing experience at Unipres UK, working in key departments, which has allowed me to grow as an individual and influenced my attitude to teamwork, training, communication, and being a customer-centric employee that adds value to the production process. It has also aided my development in respect to being able to embrace the opportunity to solve problems and meet the customers' expectations in the delivery of a compliant manufactured product to specification. In relation to my behaviors and values I promote a strong result focused approach, a professional attitude with trust, respect, integrity and honesty at its core. Through utilising these strengths and qualities, I believe I am equipped with the experience to assist the business in its drive to optimise value, be successful and deliver a world class product/service that matches the customers' expectations.

Email: jack.simm.design@gmail.com

Number: +44 0737584523

EDUCATION

Sep 2015 - Jun 2016

Level 3 Business Studies (BTEC)

Completed a level 3 business btec over two years, achieveing a distinction.

Sep 2016 - Jun 2021

Level 3 Engineering (BTEC)

Completed a level 3 engineering BTEC as part of an engineering apprenticeship at Unipres Uk.

Sep 2021 - Jun 2023

Manufacturing Engineering (HNC)

Completed a manufacturing engineering HNC over two years whilst working at Unipres Uk.

2023 - Present

BA Product Design (Undergraduate Degree)

Currently enroled on the second year of BA Product Design undergraduate degree at Middlesex University.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Design
 Badminton
 - Film Photography Running
 - Reading Antiques
 - Tennis Tv & Films

SKILLS

Presentations	Novice Adept Expert	UX/UI	Novice Adept Expert
Photoshop	Novice Adept Expert	Eye For Detail	Novice Adept Expert
Illustrator	Novice Adept Expert	Time Keeping	Novice Adept Expert
InDesign	Novice Adept Expert	Creativity	Novice Adept Expert
HTML/CSS	Novice Adept Expert	Animation	Novice Adept Expert
Communication	Novice Adept Expert	Typography	Novice Adept Expert
Team Player	Novice Adept Expert	Layouts	Novice Adept Expert

WORK HISTORY

Unipres

Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

Engineering Maintenance Technician

- •Develop and create Standard Operating Sheets to support manufacturing
- •Follow-up on design improvements and coordinate equipment changes
- •Determine root causes, process defects and support corrective action activities
- •Follow-up on design improvements and coordinate equipment changes
- •Proactively embrace objectives to improve QHSE, Productivity, Operating Cost and Delivery

Unipres

Sep 2021- Sep 2022

Cost Planning

- Develop cost reduction activities
- •Work with cross functional team to ensure successful builds are realised to customer specification
- •Creating CAD design schemes, detail design and production of Technical Data Packs.

Unipres

Sep 2022 - Jun 2023

Kaizen Team

- •Work with all stakeholders to ensure design solutions are to customer requirements
- •Delivering mechanical design solutions to time, cost, quality, and project milestones
- •Work with cross functional team to ensure successful builds are realised to customer specification
- •Proactively embrace objectives to improve QHSE, Productivity, Operating Cost and Delivery

Fabb Brothers Mar 2024 - Sep 2024

Product Development Manager

- •Oversaw the day to day operations of sales and distribution at the companies main workshop
- •Liased with suppliers and artisan craftsman on key production projects as well as consultancy design projects.
- •Lead R&D projects for new product ranges as well as enhancing existing products.